[Music]
y' think too small I got Big Dreams you
just starting them way ahead at the end
scenes started reading and dodging all
the quick sches money like your
[Music]
Spotify hi I'm Sarah and I'm Daniel and
this is the dealmakers podcast episode
18 and we have S boss here who is a
fantastic a guy with an accounting
practice background but entrepreneur who
is the owner of snap advisory in
California former client of mine and I
would love for you to give more
background sad but um one of the things
that I wanted to uh kind of point out is
um you were a former client you have
closed on deals you're running deals um
and as you know our podcast is about
kind of adding color to this fantasy of
how easy it is to buy a a business and
then sail off into the sunset um so
you're doing that are you on a boat
right now in the Mediterranean are you
in the sunset is everything has your
whole life been made really simple I
think we all know the answer to that and
which is it is horrible everything's
difficult everything's a pain I'm tired
constantly it's kind of like having
another child right like you just uh
nothing ever goes right and sometimes it
does right and you get so happy for like
the little things yeah like uh I guess
maybe it's fatherhood mixed with like
the business but I've noticed myself
getting more and more emotional when it
comes to these like like Cent the other
day was like hey thanks so much I know
you're so busy I appreciate you and I
was like oh thank you I appreciate you
like it's like the littlest things will
they just get me I'm like you're welcome
I am working hard for you I appreciate
you notice that's wonderful so give a
little bit of a background how did you
decide you wanted to buy an accounting
practice and when did you close on it we
closed last November so November 2023 um
and I originally you know I I was unsure
of exactly which direction I wanted to
go uh I originally started it was just
me uh handful of clients I primarily
focused on fractional CFO or interim CFO
type work uh right before that I had
been doing some Consulting uh with like
m&a transaction advisory work with a lot
of private Equity companies um and
actually kind of got the idea in my head
I was like you know what made a lot of
people a lot of money and you know uh
and I'm like and I've been killing
myself the whole time so I'm like hey I
should do this and you know I should be
working this hard for myself um and then
you also see everything they're doing
and you're like hey you know they don't
always take your advice and you're like
I could do this better uh my original
thought was you know what I'm gonna do
that I'm gonna acquire business I'm
doing this already um and I was looking
for anything that wasn't an accounting
firm I think I remember I was all like
product product is good I can scale
products people are hard um and lo and
behold you know I ended up with an
accounting firm um so I went through the
thing was that that was really nice I
really helped uh working with other
business owners too was just going
through so many deals before I even
decided on an industry so originally it
was actually much harder right so so in
the in the Searcher space when you're
searching for a business to buy they
they tell you hey get your thesis going
get you know Focus uh focus on an
industry focus on this um and originally
I was searching part-time which made it
that much more difficult because you're
really limited on time so when you start
really valuing your time a lot more you
start you start being extremely picky uh
you know you you just immediately try to
get to a no as fast as you can on any
deal and you know just start going
through deals it's the numbers thing
just just like most things with sales
and leads right you're getting leads for
deals you're you're going through them
and you're making contact with the
Brokers okay this one's out this one's
out um and eventually when I when I
settled on okay you know what an
accounting firm you know I I keep
getting drawn back to it it's what I
know um and just knowing everything I
know about the industry it's it's very
you know that the saying uh and I forget
I I I heard it from a lady on on one of
the conferences I was at she's like you
know accounting has a PMS problem and
she said it's pale male and stale um and
it's very traditional it's very you know
old school it's very paper
based and it's very uh kind of spread
out when it and you know it's always an
individual it's all centered around the
individual that's really hard to
replicate it's really hard to scale it's
really hard to transfer from one owner
to the the other so I I you know kind of
had this idea okay you know maybe an
accounting rollup um when I say rollup
it's really just I want to want to build
a good firm like a decent sized firm not
too huge enough that I still can
interact with some of the clients I can
step in where needed um but you know
just just a good place to that people
want to work and people are providing a
good product um and and you know I try
to productize the service so that we can
have kind of that consistent level let's
go let's go back to the beginning real
quick so first of all I mean I'm so glad
to have you on the podcast I'm looking
forward to hearing uh you know all the
details but where did this all begin did
you know you wanted to be an accountant
like in school was it like your
childhood dream where did this begin
early on uh I didn't know what I exactly
wanted so I came from a small business
background you know my dad had a a shop
he would import goods and wholesale them
uh in Downtown LA and um so I kind of
and those were my Summers so I would go
and I would actually just kind of work
there you know I do everything from uh
you know handling clients to inventory
deliveries to to to the plumbing I I did
the paint we we acquired a a warehouse
and I you know went to Home Depot got
the spray painter and like sprayed an
entire Warehouse of paint like it was it
was interesting that's entrepreneurship
though right there like that's that's
the perfect example of it because so you
want to get into importing by the way
you're painting too and doing PL you're
the plum you're the j i I honestly have
been debating like you know CU because I
think on LinkedIn especially you know
you know having that CEO title or having
the the founder title it's a little
pretentious in my opinion so I'm always
like literally the janitor like I will
do you know it's just there's just
problems and I need to fix them like I
you're scaling a business I would much
rather someone else deal with like most
of the things that I deal with but here
we are that's a major challenge with a
lot of a lot of business buyers so I
find so many people coming out of
corporate that are like middle
management like director VP level they
go and they want to buy a small business
boring business and then they're very
surprised what what all that entails
funny enough that's part of my sales
pitch is like hey you got into business
to do this or you became an engineer to
do engineering not to do your
bookkeeping let us handle that for you
we take care of this and that um and
it's 100% true it's the same thing I try
to do with my marketing you know I would
love nothing more than to have a
marketing company I'm just like here's
some money just take care of all of it
for me and you tell me what I'm missing
right like um I try to get this into my
staff as well when it comes to just the
tax side um you know when it comes to
and it's maybe just a customer service
thing where uh I noticed this a lot with
tax professionals they're like well this
is my system and they didn't fill this
out in the organizer they didn't tell me
about this and I'm like yeah but like
you the professional like something
should have been like let me just double
check with them you know if they have
foreign income they probably have a
foreign bank account it doesn't matter
if they Mark no on the tax return right
like they explicitly said they do not
have one but I'm pretty sure they do
because you're getting you're getting
some euros and you're getting deposited
somewhere and it's not a US account so I
mean those types of things I really try
to push and it's really hard to put that
into your processes nobody cares as much
as about your business and your clients
as you do so I my my plan now at least
has been to like let me focus on
training training training like always
kind of try to bring your staff up is
the best way to kind of replicate
yourself but it's so hard to go because
if you're an employee like you said if
you're a middle manager you're not not
used to that level like you you might be
a great midle manager you might put out
great work product but is that a you
know it's it it's not exactly the same
as like making sure that the letterhead
is perfect so that when someone else
does it it comes out the way you needed
to so it's a good reflection on you
company well and that's like such a such
a buyer beware call out for Professional
Services firms because so this this was
brought to the Forefront of my mind the
other day I tried to write my own
agreement and uh Sarah was kind enough
to look at it for me and and pointed out
something that wasn't there and it's so
it wasn't that I couldn't go online and
pull a TR a a template it wasn't that I
couldn't go to chat gbt the problem was
I didn't know what I didn't know so the
value is from a professional service
perspective isn't isn't necessarily just
in what we know it's it's being able to
look at a tax return and say hey this is
there but so this other thing should
probably be there too and um I mean
that's so incredibly difficult to
replicate I mean 100% anybody can do it
cheaper than us right you can do you c i
you know you can do your own contracts
you can do your own marketing you can do
your own bookkeeping it's going to be
cheaper is it going to be as good never
it can't be you just don't have the
years of experience on what to do in
different scenarios it's it's experience
over education regardless of anything
and chaty PT is not to the point where
it can be like what am I missing it's
good it's great actually it's phenomenal
but it's still not where you where it
can replace a person part two to that is
you know a lot of people are like hey
are you not afraid of AI replacing uh
the things and I'm like no because guess
what QuickBooks has been trying to sell
you on 20 years of like you don't need
an accountant do your own
bookkeeping and it's the best thing for
my industry ever uh so same thing with
AI like you someone still has to learn
how to use AI it's a tool at the end of
the day now there's going to be shifts
of course and you better know how to use
it to you know improve your productivity
and integrate it into your Tech stack
but um replacement wise I'm not too
concerned and in the businesses like law
and accounting where one sentence or one
miss number can cost you tens of
thousands of dollars it's better to have
somebody else responsible for that it
still answers the question you ask and
that's what we do in Professional
Services is like to to the annoyance of
our clients is we don't answer the
question they asked so we answer all
kinds of questions they should have
asked
so but H I want to hear sad about prior
to my involvement you know all of these
deals that you went through and I loved
the way you said getting to know as
quickly as possible because as you know
that's like exactly my goal is just
efficiency and like breaking the deal if
it's going to break quick so you can
move on were were you already
self-employed I I just want to make sure
we have this context I think we have a I
Don't Want to Miss a SP I think it's we
really relevant to how you found this
deal so were you did you go from so you
went from school you got into accounting
first after entrepreneurship and then
accounting or door too sales 100%
businesses right uh I was I gradu so I
graduated around 2009 you know uh not
not the best time and I'm actually a
finance major right so the thing was uh
you're finance major you're like all
right I got a Bachelor's degree people
going to want to hire me and then
everyone was like hey you can sell
insurance you can sell real estate you
can sell Securities and I was like uh
what about I wasn't smart enough to be a
financial analyst right to the big bank
so I was like okay so then what do I do
now I know I'll go into accounting
that'll be a backup so back then that's
all you needed to sit for the CPA exams
was an accounting minor um and I did
much better in my higher level classes
just because they were a lot more
engaging so I was like okay let me do
that uh and then even with that with my
accounting minor and like you know the
non-traditional accountant still found
it hard to this I guess this is 2010
found it hard to actually get um
accounting related role so here I
am 100% commission roll like just like
you know going door too these businesses
trying to sell Verizon services at the
time you know um great great experience
I highly recommend sales to as like as
many people as possible I hated it it's
not for me but the experience was great
the training was great there's nothing
like pounding pavement to to really get
that in fact I was actually thinking the
other day like I should do that for my
firm I'm not even joking like just go to
a bunch of businesses I don't think I've
ever heard of a CPA going into a
business and being like hey do you need
a CP we see if I ever get the guts to
pull that one off um and then from there
uh I went to you know I did some um went
into property management and then I went
into and then I finally got into working
with uh CPA a local CPA I actually met
him as I was selling him a little mini
fridge on
Craigslist and we just started talking
and like I can a job at an accounting
firm so and then that's where I got
started really and I and I was very
focus on the business side because for
the businesses we handle the bookkeeping
then we and then as you handle that they
ask you a ton of other questions on
things that are completely unrelated uh
and around back back then too um this is
still uh still early internet when it
came to things like your dropboxes and
your Google Drives and your syncing
things so I Implement I did a lot of it
work as well so we were probably one of
the first firms to do a lot of this
stuff remotely including like QuickBooks
QuickBooks desktop is a great example
it's a horrible horrible product because
it's desktop based and everything's
online now so you have to like rent a
server to be able to get it well uh I
was able to just put it in Dropbox and
as long as only one person was in the
file you're okay you don't get conflicts
um but it was mostly me right it it was
uh either I was at it at the office or I
was using the file at home and then
Dropbox would sync the two so as long as
I didn't accidentally leave it open when
I left for the day it was all good um so
working with business owners I got a ton
of experience that way I eventually
moved into more of a Consulting role
that was more like a a like fractional
CFO based and again on your own or in
that firm no no no different different
firm altogether so this was a consultant
company and they focused on no tax just
uh just fractional CFO um and from
there uh and that was my first foray and
that is probably where I learned the
most just because you have like five to
you know six seven clients sometimes and
this is again pre Digital internet so
you dve from one client to the other
right so this is in La so I'm like in
the morning I'm like driving you know
6:00 a.m. 5:30 a.m. to get to you know
from the Inland Empire to the Santa
Monica area for one of my clients there
um and you know at night there's tons of
traffic so I'm like staying in my car
getting some fast food and studying for
my CPA exams and how lucky though I mean
even today 2024 there's not a lot of
dedicated fractional CFO firms so to get
in and get that experience for an
advisory accountant I I'm right there
with you I
was not great at punching numbers into a
tax return so advisory accounting was a
better fit for me too so I I mean that's
awesome that you get to do that focus on
that regardless of how often I get
involved I I am the one that finds the
problems and the returns and I'm fixing
them I Stumble my way through the fixes
right uh because I know what the end
product's supposed to be and if you know
that then you're just like I don't know
what it is but I know it's not this so
then you just keep working through it
and you kind of figure it out and you go
from there or you bringing somebody else
in thankfully um maybe my networking has
been great with other businesses but it
has been great with other CPAs so I have
been able to find you know good
resources that I can call and ask
questions for uh and that's that's a big
big part especially if you're a solo uh
solo owner right you're you're like who
do you talk to when you network when
you're like researching and it's like
ask a tax professional you're like
I am the tax
professional like H your own lawyer and
you're like I got it open
it yeah consult your lawyer and I'm like
oh
that's very demoralizing yeah but you
know my husband's a physician and a lot
of our friends are too and they're on
there too being like oh no it says
consult your doctor like I'm I'm in the
hospital I'm the
doctor and that's that's the thing you
find out right and and you know you talk
to other firm owners and are like yeah I
have no idea either like we'll just
we're gonna have to figure it out we'll
try it out and we'll see and if there's
a problem we'll go from there it's
amazing what happens when like you get
into a position where you see what's
possible so like you're in you're in
private Equity you're doing the you're
looking at these m&a deals and you
realize like you said like you said in
the beginning that you're making other
people rich and you're like wait I could
do this for me so is that when you made
that
transition yeah so I mean imagine
imagine doing that Consulting role and
then also looking part-time it was it
was the worst uh because you're already
putting in a ton of hours then you're
trying to close on some other deals I
thought it would be good to start with a
partner so somebody who already had an
established CPA firm and I was like hey
I can you know we can do it a couple of
ways but um it's always hard with
Partners um because because you may not
always be 100% aligned it's hard selling
your your your vision so to speak and
the other thing too is you you don't
know how committed they are so I kind of
went through a couple people I went back
to actually the the original firm owner
that I worked for for the first time uh
back when I started my career uh and we
were kind of going through it so we
found a couple of deals that might work
but it was kind of the same problem
where it was still a very traditional
firm um so it's hard for me to even get
him on board onto the changes um because
there's always that fear
of well what are we going to do with
this what are we going to do with that
are we going to change things so then I
decided of course to do do it on my own
and then that that search process I will
say one thing that was much easier when
I decided what exactly I wanted it
became much easier because now I know
what I'm looking for before it was a
wide net so you're looking everywhere
when you decide I want an accounting
firm and then when you start even
getting smaller like like you're like
okay maybe not Nationwide I want it more
localized and I wanted to do these
things and I want it to you know have
all this stuff I don't want any you know
I don't want the average fees to be like
$300 for a tax return uh because I'm not
buying an ancient R Block right so um
you start getting all these filters in
and makes it so much faster to go to a
no because immediately before it even
comes to you right you you can have the
the Brokers and of course there's
Brokers that specialize in nothing but
that accounting n actually there's
multiple Brokers that do that same thing
is true for multiple other Industries
there's Brokers that do nothing but this
type of business it's it's a little bit
harder in many other Industries um you
know like manufacturing that I haven't
really seen a broker that's like I only
do manufacturing or something like that
they're they're all relatively open uh
but you but you also get used to okay
the deals coming from this broker tend
to be this the deals coming from that
broker come to be this this broker is
just full of it this broker is like you
know really go being being a good broker
in terms of okay they're truly vetting
me versus just giving me a hard time um
and or you have the Brokers that are
like trying to make this deal happen
you're like none of that makes sense I
wouldn't sell this business to me it
doesn't even make sense like why like
okay you your BS meter starts going off
and off especially when you're when when
you're really focused when it's your
money on the line right when your house
is on the line because you're do you're
doing a personal guarantee for the SBA
you start becoming really like
perceptive about a l lot of this stuff
that's such a great testimony for that I
I talk to buyers all the time and
they're like hey keep an eye out for a
deal for me and I'll ask them what
industry they're interested in like oh
anything anything that cash flows it's
like okay this is gonna be a hard Road
um so I love the fact that you said it
gets easier when you when you pick an
industry sounds like an industry that
you have a background in also helped
because you could have that BS meter and
then picking an industry that you have
experience in where you have a BS meter
and there are Brokers that specialize I
mean now you're just really simplifying
the process still very complicated as
I'm sure you're going to tell us but um
but much easier much easier Road right I
mean and it's you can apply the same
thing to to most marketing right if you
got if you if you're like hey so I
started networking more with people just
hey we we're in the same industry like
let's talk or we're we're doing this and
you know at the end of the calls uh most
people are kind of enough to be like hey
so how can I help you like what can I
send your way if you just say oh just
anything you what are they really you'll
never get anything you never get
anything so so you know a core to
marketing is like have a clear message
same thing for anything you do in life
right you tell this to your kids too
like hey what are you doing like what's
your goal what what's what's the plan
here uh so same thing with what you're
looking for in a business you can't be
I'll just look for anything got to be
more and more specific so you finally
found a deal and I I want to get into
the I want to hear about the deal I want
to hear about how the actual transaction
happened and and if you if it was easier
if you had struggles but but context to
that did you did you did you seek out a
niche firm or did you plan on buying a
firm that you were then going to Niche I
was having a hard time just getting to
where I am now with okay like these are
the filters I'm looking for I'm it's it
was incredibly hard for me because you
know to a certain degree you don't know
what you don't know like you know the
accounting work but you don't know the
um the process of buying another firm
like I've been on many deals but there
you know you had teams of people on both
sides of the buyer and seller deal like
it's completely different and you don't
have nearly as much support when you go
Downstream you know when you had teams
with people everyone's just trying to
cover their butts like I did my thing
like boom boom and then this is like
here you go someone else reviewed it now
it's just you and if you get lazy that
that's on you right or if you miss
something that's on you so it's you know
highly stressful you're trying to figure
it out um and the and regardless of how
many deals you do it just hits different
when it's when it's you doing everything
you're making a call you do not have
anyone you can really talk to even if
you have an adviser you know they're
going to advise you but they're not
going to make that call for you you're
ultimately responsible so it's
completely different when it comes to um
you know your experiences doing it for
other people versus doing it for
yourself um so so that that was a big
problem and actually this was my second
deal my first
deal lots of Lessons Learned lots of
expensive Lessons Learned um lots of
legal fees paid uh thankfully okay so
here's the big thing that saved me a ton
of money is I did my own due diligence
and because I've done quality of
earnings because because I've you know
dealt in delve into a lot of this stuff
because I know the industry I I you know
save tens of thousands of dollars
compared to anybody else that was doing
the same thing I was I couldn't say that
for the legal side of things so uh so I
still had to spend but um what got me
was this one deal that fell through you
know you still got to pay for those
legal expenses so I ended up you know
losing at least a little under 10k on
that deal and you know the biggest
lesson there was
like you know be sure be sure the the
the sellers in and never ever ever do an
Loi that isn't
exclusive like that's a good lesson I
was I was learning get desperate at the
time and that's when it really that's
when you make mistakes right because
you're you're tired you've been looking
and you just want to move forward and
you find a good enough deal which is
okay good enough is a good standard to
go by because nothing's going to be
perfect but um you know that one little
kind of thing where you you're like okay
that's okay I understand where you guys
are coming from um and then then you
really do yourself a extreme you know
big disservice because at any time
something can come in and sweep it off
from away from you and then there's no
guarantee that your funds or your you
know you're getting that all that time
and you know those expenses back so
hindsight being 2020 say you're some
listener out there you have $300,000 you
saved it up or you inherited it what's
your budget now that you know what you
know right because you may have the 10%
down for $3 million deal but if you have
300 Grand how much are you setting aside
for for burned deals so you can find the
right one oh interesting um I guess it
depends on a lot uh but if you're
self-funded I mean you you better be
sure right if you have 300K hey you
can't afford a $3 million deal like
that's 10% what where all the fees going
to come from like if you have 300,000
you could maybe maybe afford a million
dollar deal maybe like there you go
that's kind of truth you don't get from
the influencers yeah yeah yeah no it's
10% get out of here what are you gonna
do when you just acquired the firm uh
and you know the priv the AR doesn't
come with the firm so like all the
receivables all the Billings that they
have to do even if you if there is AR um
there there's working capital needs oh
my God I can't tell you how many and
this is just from like the fractional
CFO side right like people are just bad
at cash management and they don't even
know what working capital is and and
it's just like you need money in the
buiness like at any given time the
business is eating up like you know
thousands of doll tens of thousand maybe
even 100 thousand depending on how big
it is if it has inventory oh that 300
isn't going anywhere like you can maybe
afford a half a million dollar business
if there's inventory involved like get
out of here like all that money that's
going to be just sitting there and then
your payroll comes up you already spent
all your money on the 10% down payment
how are you going to make payroll right
like it's a it's a it's a real thing so
even with the traditional CPA firms
all the revenue not all but majority of
the revenue comes in at four months a
year maybe so if if it is a traditional
model where you're just doing tax work
once a year what are you going to do for
the rest of the time you have full-time
staff you got to pay for you can't just
save up all your money and then like you
know try to
desperately uh ration it out for the
rest of the year uh which is why you
know I focus on the let's say the modern
I'll get to that in a second but anyway
so so that was you know the deals
falling through and all that other stuff
right the my deal I I'll talk about it
in a little bit but like I put in the
minimal amount of cash possible because
ay I'm a big fan of Leverage but B I
knew I was going to need cash for for so
many things you know I know that I
didn't know what I was going to need
that cash for so it was very important
that I had cash available and including
other debt available outside of you know
my line of credit and outside of the SBA
financing just to be able to make sure
that I don't you know mess this up now
it's really hard to mess up a CPA firm
right you never heard of a CPA firm
going out of business um but you know
when you have a large debt payment that
changes things a little bit my whole
idea was you know to not be in you know
not be working in the business working
on the business but that's expensive to
do especially so like any any funds left
over would been go to Debt Service uh so
then you better have a very good growth
strategy which I thought I did right uh
but no I did not so um so then consider
it motivation for you know concentrating
on your marketing plan concentrating on
ways to grow the business and you know
optimize it as much as possible so the
deal that didn't go through with that
letter in intent that was non exclusive
um I don't I don't have any memory of
that this was before we met this before
we met so so that's a nice little uh uh
you know kind of segue but also a nice
little ad for Sarah like Sarah wouldn't
have let me do that
[Laughter]
thanks thanks
sad but you know I am like when I first
started out on my own and leaving the
large Law Firm I focus on startups and
they would say do you have any like
special deals for startups and my
special deal for startups was
prioritizing like I'm not going to do
everything you need all at once and then
charge you for it I'm going to do things
you absolutely critically have to have
at the juncture you absolutely
critically have to have them so that if
it doesn't take off you haven't like
invested a bunch and always trying to
toggle that and make sure so like the
legal spin the bulk comes in the trans
transaction documents um and I try it
you know people are different and when
they want those but usually like
commitment letter Loi diligence done
Prim you know on-site visits have
happened maybe you've even met with the
employees is a pretty safe time yep all
of that was done this was like purchase
agreement was about to be signed like
and then you know like that that was a
big thing with the LOI like well you
know they shouldn't have been looking at
anybody else at
all right so it's like well you know
because all all all the time spent for
the due diligence I mean that would have
been an extreme cost right um and then
all the time you know going out there
physically meeting with the meeting with
the staff uh kind of getting to know
everything digging through everything
just all that time you're never getting
back so uh so be very sure like when you
commit and if the seller is not willing
to commit that's fine there's there are
other deals out there like you're
it's painful to say no and you know
stick to your guns but you're going to
thank yourself much later the different
paths you can take into this it creates
such an interesting chain of events
because I find that when you go from
private Equity to buying a Main Street
deal or when you learn from people who
come from private Equity or Investment
Banking versus like the old school
business brokers so I get to see both
sides of it the old school business
brokers don't even really do Lois they
go straight to a purchase agreement with
a due diligence built in but it's
because on one side yes you're locking
in that buyer so you're more likely to
have a deal go through but you're also
getting a commitment from the seller
it's really saying like Hey we're all in
this we're all committing there's still
a way out with diligence but it's such a
more solid starting point and I didn't
come from like I got into that later
after I learned the LOI side so when I
got into I was like I was like no Lois
are better who's going to sign a
contract now that I've seen some deals
go SI sideways yeah I get it I get the
perspective
Daniel that's the terrible depends on
the deal size it does it does and
there's so much so yeah there's no right
answer I mean either way it could go
wrong there's a little bit of a right
answer but like pros and cons everything
you should have been doing deals when
the pandemic happened in March and a
whole bunch of people had signed a
purchase agreement that had no financing
contingency and all the SBA
Loans and so now everyone was
contractually obligated to somehow come
up with like $3 million out of their own
pocket to do a deal so like the right
purchase agreement would have that
contingency right like actually that's
funny you say that that is why my deal
fell through because I would not let go
of the financing
contingency and some other guy was they
came in with cash right so so he didn't
care so I'm like yeah okay uh but it was
one of those things like I
again first deal financing it on my own
if financing fell through you know you
lose your earnest deposit like you you
lose
your you got nothing to go back on so
like I couldn't afford to do that so I
so then you know I gave him a lot what I
could but then when it really came down
to it I was not willing to give that up
what about the deal that went through so
the deal that went through was was
fairly good um and it really matters the
seller the seller does matter um of
course you're always going to find
things after the fact and you're like
well that wasn't exactly how you
presented it but I guess it's on me for
not doing enough due diligence um but
you know that being said like it's still
like you have to have a good
relationship with a seller because there
will be problems after the fact and you
need their help to solve them um so as
much as you know and you can put it into
the agreement like oh you're going to do
so many hours of work and you're going
to you know consult on this and blah
blah blah none of that really matters
after after the money exchanges hands
like good luck with
anything 100% of the time I think it's
extremely important to have uh seller
financing so you the seller has to have
skin in the game in part as part of your
success um it varies by industry but for
me that's like a bare minimum like it it
always needs to be at least like a 10%
or something um and then having having
things to having something in there so
that the seller so you have some way to
you know Rectify any issues because for
accounting firms specifically we have
Revenue guarantees right uh but if you
pay for the 100% for the firm good luck
getting that money back I haven't seen a
revenue guarantee go through lately I
mean I haven't seen and Sarah se's way
more deals than I do so take that with a
grain of salt but like of the deals I've
seen I haven't seen any any sellers
agree to a revenue guarantee because of
the number of buyers out there right now
yeah it's getting expensive to buy but
here and and then the horrible part of
this too is they're not even good firms
like they're not even good deals and
they're getting like these stupid offers
and I'm just like I I can't like justify
it um and you know my thing's always
been and this is the business side of me
is I'm just like how can I make you know
how can I make solve this problem how
can I make this work what's the best
deal possible and for those of the of
listeners that don't know like when
you're in an industry uh you can you can
get 100% financing if you go for another
business that's in the same industry you
usually um the you know same code as you
and from there you could do 100%
financing the thing is the interest
ratees about 10.5% right now uh so so it
better be a good cash flowing deal one
caveat to that so that you have the same
next code or na ICS code but um they
will let you get by with a little bit
leaner of a cash flow on the Target
because they're not going to make you
build in your own salary like they did
on the initial one of course of course
so so like and we're we're always
talking like kind of iida but of course
you don't need to duplicate yourself
however if you're any sane person right
if you're buying a firm from another
person that person's retiring you got a
full-time head and if it's a firm owner
it's more than a full-time head that
you're replacing that's true so and and
that whoever you're replacing they're
never going to do as good of a job as a
firm owner anyway so it's like okay yes
that's true but you better be factoring
in the fact that down you have more
probably more than a full times worth of
work that you need to hire in for and
yes the bank will finance many deals
that might not make sense for you as a
buyer I could get financing for a lot of
this stuff I still think it's a bad idea
because I don't want to cut it that
close I know I whatever it is I just
know there's additional expenses I know
it's cutting it tight and there's just
so much more work for not much of a
payoff so you got to be very careful you
can get there are banks that will
finance you even if it's even the de
debt coverage ratio is like very low and
and you you know you might take some
Liberties or you might be very liberal
with that forecast of yours but you know
who's really paying the price at the end
of the day if this doesn't work out so
so that's one thing I like to remind
people and that's I guess more and more
on the tax planning side or on business
planning side I have clients come to me
and ask a ton of questions and they're
like should I do this deal and it might
be real estate or something like that
right because it's just good they want
the depreciation they want this and I'm
like sure yeah this is what it looks
like when we do your taxes you say this
much this much this much now oh by the
way if I take all that out of here and I
just look at the cash flow these tax
savings are going to cost you an extra
100K a year um so I'm very like cash
focused like cash over everything right
I will fin I will you know get as much
debt as I as I want but I will make sure
that the cash flow is there to support
the debt I make sure that there's
something that works but it's you know
it's a common business practice versus
what you would see in in like a textbook
or or somebody who concentrates on
nothing but tax focus on the industry
that you understand uh work with a
professional make sure you have
exclusivity in the LOI how do you track
your freaking deals and it's basically
how to use HubSpot to track your deals
and it's extremely helpful because if
you're talking to so many Brokers um you
know you don't know which like when
people called me I was like hi hi so and
so like oh and what is this for exactly
and you know they get offended and I'm
like I'm looking for many businesses I
don't know who you are but hubot does
this nice thing it kind of pops up and
tells you exactly what deal and what
phone number put some clarity to that
for the last couple minutes I'd love for
you to tell anyone that's listening who
needs a cash flow focused accountant
advisor uh if someone's trying to buy a
deal how can they reach you how can you
help them uh what would you like the
listeners to know about you and your
services if anybody wants to connect
with me just go to snap advisory.com uh
there's like a calendar in there you can
just schedule a meeting with me directly
and try to make it as painless as
possible unless you're trying to sell me
something in which case shoot an email
info@ snap advisory and we'll see how
that goes but um where I concentrate
honestly like on my stuff is I figure
hey uh when it comes to the Searchers
the people that are listening to this
podcast that you know they probably use
a little bit of a help um with just just
maybe like a little Consulting but then
if I'm able to provide some value to
them in that initial call or something
when they do Acquire The Firm they're
going to need that bookkeeping service
they're going to need that you know Tax
Service and hopefully that kind of
converts over for the individual side
you know the big focus in the CPA
industry right now has been getting away
from the solo below 1040 work because
you're then you're competing with the
H&R Blocks um but to focus on tax
planning you know somebody people
generally I I want at least the ones I
want to focus on want a continuous
relationship with their CPA throughout
the year versus just during tax time and
it works better too you have fewer
clients you can concentrate you can
service them better uh and from there
you actually understand your clients
better because now you're not managing
300 clients maybe you're managing 50 to
100 clients per per CPA or per e or
whatever you want to go with them I mean
I I sent you referrals because I think
you're a very unique option because
California which is great you know like
it's really helpful to have somebody who
knows California tax um and you're so
entrepreneurial um so I feel like you
know there's a lot of competition for um
you know in the valley for you know
there's really really expensive options
that can service entrepreneurial
companies um in California finding a
person that's got a smaller shop and a
more like Boutique practice that still
has that competency is very rare and
that's it's a very valid point because
the the biggest thing with advisory is I
need good data in order to advise people
and every and that that's the reason I
started focusing more on like the simple
bookkeeping stuff is because before that
if you don't have clean books I can't
really advise you on anything like you
know most of the stuff I think is very
valuable right like when we do the
bookkeeping it's replacing
like a bookkeeper you would have had to
hire or your admin person that probably
doesn't know exactly what she's doing
anyways so I'm like hey you have to do
this either way either it's your time
your admin's time somebody's time and
regardless of what it costs like pay a
professional to do their thing that's
one less thing you have to worry about
you can concentrate on you and then when
you're ready for for that actual you
know maybe some that fractional CFO to
bring on somebody to you know maybe help
with cash flow or help with any of this
stuff we have our foundation for the
numbers that's accurate thank you so
much for coming on and talking us
through your origin story and your deal
and and sharing all the insights we're
going to have to have you back to do
some deep dives into some of these
things because I feel like we we just
scraped the surface the the biggest
thing honestly that that a lot of people
should take away from this is don't buy
a business because it is that much of a
pain I'm not even joking just I know
you're not you you you think you know
but you don't right um so unless you're
unless you're like ready for a lot of
pain then just know that you're getting
into yourself into something you have no
idea what you're getting yourself into
episode 18 just don't even buy a
business this is it this will be the
last episode we're done we wrap it up
cut this is the end all right all of all
of the links and resources will be in
the in the show notes uh s if you want
me to share anything send it over I'll
I'll make sure it's in the show notes
for everyone and yeah can't wait to have
you back to do a deep dive into some of
these uh more in-depth concepts for
people if you're open to it oh
definitely oh you guys are amazing uh
you know I will I mean Sarah already
knows I tell her this all the time time
like it's great you're great nice to
meet you Daniel and thanks for having me
on brother